ANKUR SHAHI

Mississauga, ON L4Z 1C6

Phone: (647) 388-2109 | Email: shahiankur80@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ankur-shahi| GitHub: https://github.com/ankurshahi80

Portfolio: http://ankurshahi80.github.io/react-portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack web developer who uses his instructional designing experiences to define and build user-centric MVP apps. A strategic, futuristic, and focused professional with a proven record of effectively interacting at all levels and managing Agile projects. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies Coding Boot Camp.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, React, SQL, NoSQL, Handlebars

Applications: Git, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku

Tools: Express, Node, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Local Storage, Session Storage, IndexedDB

PROJECTS

Run Buddy | https://github.com/ankurshahi80/run-buddy | https://ankurshahi80.github.io/run-buddy/

- Summary: A marketing app for the Run Buddy group to generate leads
- Role: Sole author
- Languages used: HTML and CSS

Coworkers|https://github.com/Group2Project2UofTCoding/coworkers | https://coworkers-group2.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A simple employee management system that tracks employees in an organization from a manager's perspective.
- Role: Back-end developer and Project Manager
- Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Handlebars

Vintage Vinyl Records | https://github.com/group01-project03/vintage-vinyl-records | https://vintage-vinyls.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A full-stack MERN e-commerce website which allows the user to browse and purchase vintage vinyl records using their credit card.
- Role: Back-end developer and Project Manager
- Languages used: HTML, CSS, & JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Instructional Designer NIIT Learning Solutions Canada

2019 – Present Mississauga, ON

Wear multiple hats: consultant, instructional designer, and project manager. Advise a major Canadian retailer on creating learning solutions to support their enterprise IT systems launches and updates.

Key Accomplishments:

- Reduced the LMS migration cost by 2 resources by automating the bulk-upload templates in Excel VBA
- Grew revenue from \$75,000 to \$750,000 in 2019 by successfully delivering enterprise-wide IT systems training for Adobe Experience Manager, Workday, Salesforce, Saba LMS, etc.

Learning Specialist 2018 – 2019

Goeasy, Canada Mississauga, ON Designed and developed training content for organization's systems, products and services.

Key Accomplishments:

- Helped pass the \$1B consumer loan portfolio in 2019 by training financial advisors on the Credit Plus Savings Loan and Goeasy Prepaid MasterCard
- Reduced the training development time by 50% by introducing the rapid e-Learning tool Rise360

Workplace Consultant 2016 – 2018 Gallup, India Mumbai, IN

Facilitated Gallup's Strengths-based coaching sessions in India, Malaysia and Singapore.

Key Accomplishments:

- Facilitated Gallup's flagship 4½ days Accelerated Strengths Coaching Course (ASCC) across Asia with a feedback score of 4.7 out of 5
- Helped reduce training costs by facilitating in the Philippines and Singapore in addition to India

Sr. Manager, Learning and Development Thomas Cook, India

2014 - 2018

Thomas Cook, India Mumbai, IN Implemented the new-hire onboarding training and front-line sale training across 250 offices in India.

Key Accomplishments:

- Improved the onboarding rate from 40% to 80% by introducing eLearning
- Improved eSat by providing timely support and training to the front-line sales staff

Asst. Manager, Learning and Development Tech M. India

2007 – 2014 Mumbai, IN

Planned, implemented, and delivered new hire onboarding training, and process change and product launch training for 3 Global Services, UK.

Key Accomplishments:

- Onboarded 1500 customer service advisors to operations with a 90% throughput to meet the performance goals set by the business
- Created 6 instructor-led new-hire curriculum using adult-learning principles to maximize knowledge retention

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies, Toronto, ON

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, GraphQL, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.